<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</title>
    <link>/</link>
    <description>Recent content on Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    
	<atom:link href="/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>AASC2020 coming to Victoria</title>
      <link>/news/aasc2020-coming-to-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/aasc2020-coming-to-victoria/</guid>
      <description>At AASC2018, Rotorua, New Zealand, it was decided that the next Australiasia Applied Statistics Conference will be held in Victoria. Murray Hannah will chair this next AASC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register your interest</title>
      <link>/news/mailinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/mailinglist/</guid>
      <description>To be notified of future updates about AASC2020, please fill out the form here.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Code of Conduct</title>
      <link>/code_of_conduct/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/code_of_conduct/</guid>
      <description>The organizers of AASC2020 are dedicated to providing a harassment-free conference experience for everyone regardless of gender, gender expression, sexual orientation, disability, physical appearance, body size, race, or religion (or lack thereof).
All attendees, speakers, sponsors and volunteers at AASC2020 are required to agree to the following code of conduct. Organizers will enforce this code throughout and expect cooperation in ensuring a safe environment for all.
We do not tolerate harassment of AASC2020 participants in any form.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Contact</title>
      <link>/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/contact/</guid>
      <description> AASC Organising Committee  Murray Hannah (DEDJTR, Chair) Khageswor Giri (DEDJTR, Secretary) Andrew Van Burgel (DPIRD) Debra L Partington (DEDJTR) Donghui Ma (VSN) Emi Tanaka (Monash) Kym L Butler (DEDJTR) Sorn Norng (DEDJTR) Subhash Chandra (DEDJTR)  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>FAQ</title>
      <link>/faq/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/faq/</guid>
      <description>Do I have to register for the conference to sign up for the workshop?
 No. You can register for the workshop alone.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>