<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>workshop on Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</title>
    <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/categories/workshop/</link>
    <description>Recent content in workshop on Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aasc2022.netlify.com/categories/workshop/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Data Visualisation with R</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-datavis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-datavis/</guid>
      <description>Data Visualisation with R Data visualisation is a key statistical tool for effective communication and to understand aspects of data and models. The statistical language R is used widely for data analysis and visualization, e.g. the BBC Visual and Data Journalism team uses ggplot2 R-package to create production-ready charts. This workshop will teach you how to create production-ready graphics using the grammar of graphics implemented in ggplot2 R-package. The workshop will be hands-on with plenty of practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Visualization and Data Mining</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-visualization-and-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-visualization-and-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>[This workshop is now cancelled]{style=&amp;ldquo;color:red;&amp;rdquo;} and replaced with Data Visualisation with R.
Visualization and Data Mining Morning session: Sustenance for the every day statistical analysis This part covers making plots using the grammar of graphics and how this fits into statistical inference. We will use the tidyverse suite of packages and nullabor.
Afternoon session: Looking at the model in the data space This part will cover the use of tours to examine multivariate spaces, in relation to various data mining methods, including dimension reduction, supervised and unsupervised classification models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Genstat 23 Masterclass: data mining and advanced modelling</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-genstat-22-masterclass-data-mining-and-advanced-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-genstat-22-masterclass-data-mining-and-advanced-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Genstat 23 Masterclass: data mining and advanced modelling In this masterclass we will explore some of the data mining and more advanced statistical modelling facilities available in Genstat. As not all these facilities are available in the menus, the session will begin with a brief recap of Genstat’s command language.
Topics will include:
Genstat command language Data mining association rules self-organising maps discriminant analysis support vector machines classification trees and random forests k-nearest-neighbours classification Advanced modelling specialised regression (e.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
