<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>News on Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</title>
    <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/</link>
    <description>Recent content in News on Australasian Applied Statistics Conference</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-au</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Programme released</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/programme-released/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 17 Nov 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/programme-released/</guid>
      <description>Programme released</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Drs Vanessa Cave, David Baird and Roger Payne</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-cave-baird-payne/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Oct 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-cave-baird-payne/</guid>
      <description>New Developments in Genstat 22</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Dr Carolyn Huston</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-huston/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-huston/</guid>
      <description>Emulation of the Spark bushfire solver, and building trust in uncertainty</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Dr Patricia Menéndez</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-menendez/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-menendez/</guid>
      <description>Practical steps toward reproducibility</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Data Visualisation with R</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-datavis/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 09 Aug 2022 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-datavis/</guid>
      <description>Data Visualisation with R Data visualisation is a key statistical tool for effective communication and to understand aspects of data and models. The statistical language R is used widely for data analysis and visualization, e.g. the BBC Visual and Data Journalism team uses ggplot2 R-package to create production-ready charts. This workshop will teach you how to create production-ready graphics using the grammar of graphics implemented in ggplot2 R-package. The workshop will be hands-on with plenty of practical examples.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AASC2020 AGM Webinars</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/aasc2020-webinar/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 03 Dec 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/aasc2020-webinar/</guid>
      <description>The 2020 AASC AGM took place on 3 December 2020. You can find the videos of each presentation below with the abstracts.
 ASReml and Genomic models Development of Genomic tools to support ASReml-R Genstat development in difficult times CycDesigN Version 7.0 Update  ASReml and Genomic models   Arthur R Gilmour It is 50 years since Arthur began working as a biometrician with NSW DPI (1970) having majored in biometry in the 4th year of his B Sc AGr (Sydney).</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Genstat development in difficult times</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/genstat-development-in-difficult-times/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Oct 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/genstat-development-in-difficult-times/</guid>
      <description>The AASC conference is always a highlight for us at VSN, and it is a real disappointment that we cannot meet this year. Nevertheless it is good to be able to keep in touch by email, MS Teams and Zoom - and to know that you are keeping safe.
The Genstat team is dispersed over the two hemispheres, and so we are used to collaborating at a distance. Genstat development has continued almost unaffected, and I am glad to have this opportunity to tell you what we have been doing.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Improving predictions by integrating Data Science and Domain Science in Resources and the Environment</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/dare-session/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/dare-session/</guid>
      <description>Improving predictions by integrating Data Science and Domain Science in Resources and the Environment Biography Edward Cripps, deputy director of DARE centre (Data Analytics for Resources and Environments), is an Associate Professor in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at the University of WA. His research interests are in Bayesian longitudinal analysis and spatio-temporal models, and the integration of statistical and physical models. His primary applications are in the statistical modelling of environmental, meteorological and oceanographic processes and their interaction with engineering decision making and asset management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: A/Prof Edward Cripps</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-aprof-cripps/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jul 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-aprof-cripps/</guid>
      <description>Uncertainty quantification and communication for the earth sciences Biography Edward Cripps, deputy director of DARE centre (Data Analytics for Resources and Environments), is an Associate Professor in the Department of Mathematics and Statistics at the University of WA. His research interests are in Bayesian longitudinal analysis and spatio-temporal models, and the integration of statistical and physical models. His primary applications are in the statistical modelling of environmental, meteorological and oceanographic processes and their interaction with engineering decision making and asset management.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Dr Arthur Gilmour</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-arthur-gilmour/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-arthur-gilmour/</guid>
      <description>ASReML in Practice Biography: Arthur Gilmour obtained his B Sc Agr from Sydney University majoring in Biometry in 1970 with a NSW Government traineeship. He then served as a biometrician until his retirement from NSW Agriculture as a Principal Research Scientist in 2009. From the outset, he was involved in software development to meet the current statistical analysis needs of his clients and colleagues. He obtained his PhD in animal breeding from Massey University in 1983 during which time he came into contact with Robin Thompson.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Dr Petra Kuhnert</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-petra-kuhnert/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-petra-kuhnert/</guid>
      <description>Deep Learning for prediction and forecasting of Agricultural processes</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Prof Di Cook</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-prof-di-cook/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-prof-di-cook/</guid>
      <description>Data visualisation: Bridging the long-standing gap between exploratory and inferential statistics</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Visualization and Data Mining</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-visualization-and-data-mining/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Feb 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-visualization-and-data-mining/</guid>
      <description>[This workshop is now cancelled]{style=&amp;ldquo;color:red;&amp;quot;} and replaced with Data Visualisation with R.
Visualization and Data Mining Morning session: Sustenance for the every day statistical analysis This part covers making plots using the grammar of graphics and how this fits into statistical inference. We will use the tidyverse suite of packages and nullabor.
Afternoon session: Looking at the model in the data space This part will cover the use of tours to examine multivariate spaces, in relation to various data mining methods, including dimension reduction, supervised and unsupervised classification models.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Workshop: Genstat 23 Masterclass: data mining and advanced modelling</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-genstat-22-masterclass-data-mining-and-advanced-modelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 31 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/workshop-genstat-22-masterclass-data-mining-and-advanced-modelling/</guid>
      <description>Genstat 23 Masterclass: data mining and advanced modelling In this masterclass we will explore some of the data mining and more advanced statistical modelling facilities available in Genstat. As not all these facilities are available in the menus, the session will begin with a brief recap of Genstat’s command language.
Topics will include:
 Genstat command language Data mining  association rules self-organising maps discriminant analysis support vector machines classification trees and random forests k-nearest-neighbours classification   Advanced modelling  specialised regression (e.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: A/Prof Emlyn Williams</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-a-prof-emlyn-williams/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-a-prof-emlyn-williams/</guid>
      <description>The application of CycDesigN in designing experiments for use in agriculture</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Invited Speaker: Dr Francis Hui</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-francis-hui/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/invited-speaker-dr-francis-hui/</guid>
      <description>All Under One Roof – The Rise of Joint Species Distribution Modeling in Ecology</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Things to do</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/things-to-do/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/things-to-do/</guid>
      <description>&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/MchECDmC8EY&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;iframe width=&#34;560&#34; height=&#34;315&#34; src=&#34;https://www.youtube.com/embed/_aGEv5iE7PU&#34; frameborder=&#34;0&#34; allow=&#34;accelerometer; autoplay; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture&#34; allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>AASC2020 coming to Victoria</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/aasc2020-coming-to-victoria/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/aasc2020-coming-to-victoria/</guid>
      <description>At AASC2018, Rotorua, New Zealand, it was decided that the next Australasian Applied Statistics Conference will be held in Victoria. Murray Hannah will chair this next AASC.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Register your interest</title>
      <link>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/mailinglist/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Jul 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://aasc2022.netlify.com/news/mailinglist/</guid>
      <description>To be notified of future updates about AASC2020, please fill out the form here.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
